Are you ready, kids?
孩子们，你们准备好了吗？
All: Aye, aye, Captain!
全体：是啊是啊，队长！
I can't hear you.
我听不到你说话。
All: Aye, aye, Captain!
全体：是啊是啊，队长！
♪ Ohh... ♪
♪ 哦...♪
♪ Who lives in a pineapple
under the sea? ♪
♪ 谁住在菠萝里
在海底？ ♪
All: Spongebob Squarepants!
全部：海绵宝宝！
♪ Absorbent and yellow
and porous is he ♪
♪ 吸水性和黄色
他是多孔的 ♪
All: Spongebob Squarepants!
全部：海绵宝宝！
♪ If nautical nonsense
be something you wish ♪
♪ 如果是航海废话
成为你想要的东西♪
All: Spongebob Squarepants!
全部：海绵宝宝！
♪ Then drop on the deck
♪ 然后落在甲板上
-All: Spongebob Squarepants!
-Ready?
-全部：海绵宝宝！
-准备好？
All: Spongebob Squarepants!
全部：海绵宝宝！
Spongebob Squarepants!
海绵宝宝！
Spongebob
海绵宝宝
Squarepants!
方裤！
♪ ♪
Ah.
啊。
Hey, Patrick.
嘿，帕特里克。
Hey, Spongebob.
嘿，海绵宝宝。
All ready to go
jellyfishing today?
一切准备就绪，出发
今天钓水母吗？
No.
不。
Just kidding!
只是在开玩笑！
I see you even brought
your double net.
我看你还带来了
你的双网。
Yep, it's three times as fun.
是的，它的乐趣是原来的三倍。
Uh, Patrick,
don't you mean twice as fun?
呃，帕特里克，
你不是说乐趣加倍吗？
What is?
什么是？
Your--never mind.
你的——没关系。
Oh, Spongebob,
that reminds me.
哦，海绵宝宝，
这让我想起了。
We should probably check
the weather report before we go.
我们或许应该检查一下
出发前的天气预报。
Good idea.
好主意。
And now the weather.
现在是天气。
Here we go.
开始了。
Thank you, Phil.
谢谢你，菲尔。
Today's weather forecast
calls for...
今天的天气预报
呼吁...
A horrible storm will
ravage the Bikini Bottom area.
一场可怕的风暴将会
蹂躏比基尼区。
Both: A horrible storm?
两人：一场可怕的风暴？
You heard me.
你听到了。
Panic is not advised,
不建议恐慌，
although it is recommended.
虽然是推荐的。
Also, an advisory
has been issued
另外，还有一个咨询
已发出
to avoid any and all
jellyfishing if possible.
以避免任何和所有
如果可以的话，可以钓水母。
Patrick, help me
get these boards nailed up.
帕特里克，帮帮我
把这些木板钉起来。
Spongebob,
this seems like a strange time
海绵宝宝，
这似乎是一个奇怪的时刻
to start decorating.
开始装饰。
Start dec--
十二月开始——
You, sir, obviously do not
recognize fine decorating
先生，您显然不
认识精美装饰
when you see it.
当你看到它时。
Hmm.
唔。
Admire it later, Patrick.
稍后欣赏它，帕特里克。
Right now, we've got to get
my house converted
现在，我们必须得到
我的房子改建了
into a shelter capable
of withstanding extreme weather.
进入有能力的庇护所
能够承受极端天气。
You can say that again.
你可以再说一遍。
Actually, I can't.
事实上，我不能。
Why?
为什么？
Because I just stepped
on one of these nails.
因为我刚刚迈出一步
在其中一个指甲上。
♪ La-da-di
la-da-dum ♪
♪ 拉达迪
拉达杜姆 ♪
♪ La-da-doo ♪
♪ 拉达杜 ♪
Got ya.
明白了。
Now just one quick
flick of the wrist and...
现在只需快速一点
手腕一抖，然后……
Boom!
繁荣！
Oh, ho, blah.
哦，嗬，废话。
Violin.
小提琴。
Whoo, nice work, buddy.
哇，干得好，伙计。
Now my house can withstand
现在我的房子可以承受
anything nature has
to throw at us.
大自然拥有的任何东西
向我们扔。
I guess Squidward's
我猜是章鱼哥
Squidward!
章鱼哥！
Did you come to weather out
the storm with us?
你是来避暑的吗
风暴与我们同在吗？
No!
I--what storm?
不！
我——什么风暴？
The one Phil Preflumster
told us about.
菲尔·普雷弗鲁斯特 (Phil Preflumster)
告诉我们。
Who's that?
那是谁？
He's the weatherman
on the news channel.
他是天气预报员
在新闻频道上。
He said--
他说——
I can't understand
a word you're saying.
我不明白
你说的一句话。
Come on, Squidward.
It'll be fun.
来吧，章鱼哥。
会很有趣的。
While the elements rage outside,
当外面的天气肆虐时，
we'll snuggle in here
and pass the time
我们会依偎在这里
并打发时间
by playing board games
and playing Tic-Tac-Toe
通过玩棋盘游戏
和玩井字游戏
and drinking hot cocoa
和喝热可可
and playing Tic-Tac-Toe
和玩井字游戏
and doing jigsaw puzzles
and watching TV
和做拼图游戏
和看电视
and drinking hot cocoa
and doing jigsaw puzzles
和喝热可可
和做拼图游戏
and playing board games
和玩棋盘游戏
and drinking hot tea.
并喝热茶。
I thought it was cocoa!
我还以为是可可呢！
Oh, yeah.
哦，是的。
Hot cocoa...
We'll be drinking.
热可可...
我们会喝酒。
That's better.
这样更好。
Well, I think I'll pass.
嗯，我想我会通过。
Even if I let you borrow my
huggly, snuggly bunny slippers?
就算我让你借我的
拥抱、舒适的兔子拖鞋？
Hmm, I'll have
to think about that.
嗯，我会有
想想这个。
Okay,
but you better think fast,
好吧，
但你最好快速思考，
'cause Patrick here
really loves my--
因为帕特里克在这里
真的很爱我的——
Squidward, welcome back!
章鱼哥，欢迎回来！
Here's your slippers.
这是你的拖鞋。
There.
That's better.
那里。
这样更好。
What's better about it?
它有什么更好的呢？
I liked it better before,
when I could see.
以前比较喜欢
当我能看见的时候。
Squidward,
the lights went off.
章鱼哥，
灯灭了。
Yes, they did,
是的，他们做到了，
when you turned them off.
当你关闭它们时。
Spongebob!
海绵宝宝！
Patrick!
What is it?
帕特里克！
它是什么？
I never realized
how delicious your hot cocoa is.
我从来没有意识到
你的热可可多美味啊。
Oh, thank you, Patrick.
哦，谢谢你，帕特里克。
Oh, boy.
哦，男孩。
How about some of those games
you promised?
其中一些游戏怎么样
你答应了吗？
Okay, boys, let's roll
to see who goes first.
好吧，孩子们，我们滚吧
看看谁先走。
This is Tic-Tac-Toe.
这就是井字游戏。
You don't roll
to see who goes first.
你不滚
看看谁先走。
He's right.
他是对的。
You play rock-paper-scissors
for it.
你玩石头剪刀布
为了它。
Oh, yeah.
哦，是的。
One.
一。
-Two.
-Three.
-二。
-三。
Oh, it's a tie.
哦，是领带。
Darn it!
该死的！
All: One, two, three.
全体：一、二、三。
Darn it!
该死的！
I'll get you next time.
下次我来接你。
-One, two, three.
-Tie.
-一二三。
-领带。
-Darn it!
-One, two--
-该死！
-一，二--
-Tie.
-Darn it!
-领带。
-该死！
There, I win.
See?
在那里，我赢了。
看？
Hmm.
唔。
I'm not seeing
anything there.
我没看到
那里有什么东西。
Yeah, looks like
a lot of junk.
是的，看起来像
很多垃圾。
What do you mean,
you're not seeing anything?
你是什么意思，
你什么都没看到吗？
There's three in a row
right here.
连续三个
就在这里。
Tic-Tac-Toe!
井字游戏！
Easy, friend.
简单，朋友。
Yeah, relax, Squidward.
是的，放松点，章鱼哥。
We're just here to have fun.
我们只是来这里玩得开心。
Oh, okay, yeah, okay.
哦，好吧，是啊，好吧。
Here we go.
开始了。
Congratulations, Squidward.
恭喜你，章鱼哥。
Well played.
打的好。
Come on, Patrick.
You can do it.
来吧，帕特里克。
你可以做到的。
Be the puzzle piece.
成为拼图。
Cannot complete
无法完成
Difficulty level
too advanced.
难度级别
太先进了。
Rate of brain activity
increasing aging process
大脑活动率
老化过程加剧
by 30 years per second.
每秒 30 年。
Come on, grandpa.
You can do it.
来吧，爷爷。
你可以做到的。
You still got a few good years
left in you.
你还有好几年的时间
留在你里面。
Eh?
呃？
Go, Patrick!
Go!
去吧，帕特里克！
去！
Go, Patrick!
Go!
去吧，帕特里克！
去！
Go, Patrick!
Go!
去吧，帕特里克！
去！
Go, Patrick!
Go!
去吧，帕特里克！
去！
Go, Patrick!
Go!
去吧，帕特里克！
去！
I told you creatures
我告诉过你生物
I was trying to take a nap
over here.
我正想小睡一会儿
在这里。
Now, for the last time,
can't you just--
现在，最后一次，
你不能只是——
Hang on, Squidward.
坚持住，章鱼哥。
Patrick was just about
to figure out
帕特里克正要
弄清楚
where the last piece
of this puzzle goes.
最后一块在哪里
这个谜题的答案是。
Weren't you, Patrick?
不是你吗，帕特里克？
Who's the green guy?
绿衣人是谁？
It's the last piece
of the puzzle!
这是最后一块
的谜题！
There's only one place
it can go.
只有一个地方
它可以走了。
Right here!
就在这里！
Squidward.
章鱼哥。
It wasn't your turn.
还没轮到你。
That's cheating.
那是作弊。
Cheating?
作弊？
It's a jigsaw puzzle.
这是一个拼图游戏。
You can't cheat.
你不能作弊。
Oh, it's okay.
哦，没关系。
We'll just start over.
我们就重新开始吧。
I got to get out of here!
我必须离开这里！
Oh, welcome back,
Squidward.
哦，欢迎回来，
章鱼哥。
We were right about
to start figuring out
我们是对的
开始弄清楚
where this first
puzzle piece goes.
这是第一个
拼图块消失了。
Oh, maybe Squidward
can help us--
哦，也许章鱼哥
可以帮助我们——
No, he can't.
不，他不能。
Please, Squidward?
请问，章鱼哥？
-No way.
-Please.
-决不。
-请。
I have an even better idea.
我有一个更好的主意。
-What is it?
-Yeah, tell us.
-这是什么？
-是的，告诉我们。
Tell us. Tell us.
Tell us.
告诉我们。告诉我们。
告诉我们。
Tell us. Tell us. Tell us.
Tell--
告诉我们。告诉我们。告诉我们。
告诉 -
Shh.
Quiet time.
嘘。
安静的时间。
It's a game called Boundaries.
这是一个叫《边界》的游戏。
Ooh, ooh-ooh-ooh.
Ooh.
哦，哦哦哦。
哦。
Yes, Patrick?
是的，帕特里克？
Uh, will there be
any spelling in this game?
呃，会有吗
这游戏有拼写吗？
Oh, no.
No spelling.
哦，不。
没有拼写。
Yes!
是的！
It's very simple.
这很简单。
The object of the game
游戏的对象
is to see how long everyone
can leave Squidward alone.
就是看大家多久
可以让章鱼哥独自一人。
Until the storm passes,
直到暴风雨过去，
he will stay
inside boundaries
他会留下来
边界内
he defines with chalk lines
on the floor.
他用粉笔线定义
在地板上。
-I have a question.
-What?
-我有一个问题。
-什么？
Where are you gonna get
the chalk?
你要去哪里
粉笔？
I brought some!
我带了一些！
♪ ♪
Brilliant work, as usual,
Squidward.
一如既往的出色工作，
章鱼哥。
Now all I have to do
现在我要做的就是
is sit here
until this storm blows over.
坐在这里
直到这场风暴过去。
Wait a minute.
I'm starving.
等一下。
我饿死了。
Spongebob's got to have
some snacks in here somewhere.
海绵宝宝必须有
这里有一些小吃。
Ah, jackpot.
啊，中奖了。
I bet you wish you had
some of this, don't--
我打赌你希望你有
其中一些，不要——
Snail food?
蜗牛食物？
Blah!
废话！
I got to find
some real food.
我必须找到
一些真正的食物。
Maybe in the kitchen...
也许在厨房里...
Halt!
停止！
Nobody is to cross
this boundary.
没有人可以跨越
这个边界。
I'm the one
who drew this line
我就是那个
这条线是谁画的
you're not supposed to cross.
你不应该穿越。
If you are the one
who drew it,
如果你是那个人
谁画的，
let me see
your identification papers.
让我看看
您的身份证件。
Identifi--
Fine.
身份识别--
很好。
But when this storm is over,
但当这场风暴结束后
you're gonna regret this,
mister.
你会后悔的
先生。
What the--what?
I don't have them.
什么——什么？
我没有。
They must be
in my other pants.
他们一定是
在我的另一条裤子里。
Look, if you just let me cross,
I can go and get them.
听着 如果你让我过去
我可以去接他们。
Please, I promise I'll--
拜托，我保证我会——
Hmm, you may be
telling the truth.
嗯，你可能是
说实话。
Oh, thank you.
Thank you. Thank you. Thank you.
哦，谢谢。
谢谢。谢谢。谢谢。
I'm just so hungry--
我只是太饿了——
But then again,
you may not.
但话又说回来，
你可能不会。
Come with me.
We shall find out the truth.
跟我来吧。
我们将会找出真相。
Ooh, that'll be the day.
噢，那一天就会到来。
♪ ♪
Stop that cephalopod!
阻止那个头足类动物！
Hiyoh!
嗨哟！
Please.
请。
I just want to get back
onto my side of the boundary.
我只想回来
到我这边的边界。
This, I cannot allow.
这，我不能允许。
It is against the rules.
这是违反规则的。
But all I wanted
was something to eat.
但我想要的一切
是吃的东西。
Did somebody say
something to eat?
有人说过吗
有什么吃的吗？
My food!
我的食物！
Your food?
你的食物？
Hey, I want some too.
嘿嘿，我也想要一些。
Wah, wow.
哇，哇。
Is this really
what we've come to?
这真的是吗
我们到了什么程度？
Is one little storm
all it takes
是一场小风暴
所需要的一切
to turn us
into complete animals?
来改变我们
变成完整的动物？
Apparently so.
显然是这样。
Well, that and a refrigerator
full of food, anyways.
嗯，还有一个冰箱
反正吃饱了
Hey, did you hear that?
嘿，你听到了吗？
Oh, it's just Patrick
哦，这只是帕特里克
No, no, no, no,
not that.
不，不，不，不，
不是那个。
I mean from outside.
我的意思是从外面。
I don't hear anything.
我什么也没听到。
The storm must have stopped.
暴风雨应该已经停止了。
Squidward, wait!
章鱼哥，等等！
Whoo-hoo!
呼呼！
So long, suckers!
再见，傻瓜们！
Boom!
繁荣！
Curse you, Preflumster.
诅咒你，Preflumster。
♪ ♪
And good riddance.
祝你摆脱困境。
Next time,
you should read the sign
下次，
你应该阅读这个标志
about our mandatory
side of fries policy.
关于我们的强制性
薯条政策的一面。
Lookee, another bright-eyed,
bushy-tailed customer.
看，另一个眼睛明亮的人，
浓密尾巴的顾客。
But I--
But I don't--
但我——
但我不——
Want to stop spending money
here?
想要停止花钱
在这里？
Well, don't worry.
好吧，别担心。
I'm certainly not gonna keep you
from doing what you want.
我当然不会挽留你
从做你想做的事。
Give him a Krabby Patty
with the works.
给他一个蟹肉饼
与作品。
I'm not hungry.
我不饿。
Oh, that's funny.
哦，这很有趣。
I'll think about that one
while you buy some club soda.
我会考虑一下那个
当你买一些苏打水时。
Boy, you're doing it
all wrong.
男孩，你正在做这事
都错了。
Here, take this.
给，拿着这个。
Now you can flip two patties
at the same time,
现在你可以翻转两个肉饼了
同时，
do twice the work.
做两倍的工作。
Mr. Krabs, you're a--
蟹老板，你是——
Genius?
Perhaps.
天才？
也许。
Or maybe I'm just a little off.
或者也许我只是有点偏离。
Wow.
If only I was a little off.
哇。
如果我稍微偏离一点就好了。
Are you gonna
let me out of here?
你要吗
让我离开这里吗？
The formula.
公式。
Blasted flimsy nails.
脆弱的指甲被炸毁。
How am I supposed to hide
me formula in this nonsense?
我该如何隐藏
我这个废话的公式？
Oh, well,
it's the life I choose to live.
哦，好吧，
这是我选择的生活。
Did you see that?
你看到了吗？
Yeah, Krabs hides his formula
under the floor.
是的，蟹老板隐藏了他的配方
在地板下。
So what?
所以呢？
So everything!
所以一切！
That means I know
where it is.
这意味着我知道
它在哪里。
Doesn't mean
you can get to it.
并不意味着
你可以做到的。
What kind of wife...
什么样的老婆...
We'll see about that.
我们将会看到这一点。
I knew this baby
would come in handy.
我认识这个宝贝
会派上用场的。
Uh-huh.
嗯嗯。
Turn on
the navigation system, honey.
打开
导航系统，亲爱的。
Let's get this show
on the road.
让我们来看看这个节目
在路上。
Dig 50 meters.
Then turn right.
挖50米。
然后右转。
At this rate, we'll have
the formula before you can say--
按照这个速度，我们将有
公式之前你可以说——
Barnacles!
藤壶！
Now what?
现在怎么办？
It appears we've stumbled
into a mishap.
看来我们被绊倒了
陷入不幸。
Now we're stuck between a rock
and a hard place, literally.
现在我们被困在岩石之间
从字面上看，这是一个艰难的地方。
Well, let's just dig deeper
and go around it.
好吧，让我们深入挖掘一下
并绕过它。
Uh, the only problem
with that is--
呃，唯一的问题
那就是——
Shh!
嘘！
Can't you see
I'm concentrating?
你看不到吗
我专心了？
Yes!
是的！
Do you see what happens
你看到发生了什么吗
when you let me make
my own decisions?
当你让我做
我自己的决定？
Now maybe we'll get some--
现在也许我们会得到一些——
What happened?
发生了什么？
Well, right before
you started
嗯，就在之前
你开始了
making your own decisions,
自己做决定，
I was about to say we're digging
right above an underground cave.
我正想说我们正在挖掘
就在一个地下洞穴的上方。
Oh, the majesty.
哦，陛下。
I've never seen such beauty.
我从未见过如此美丽。
Sad, sob, cry, sob.
悲伤，哭泣，哭泣，哭泣。
It's such a shame
no one else can see it.
真是太可惜了
其他人都看不到它。
Sad.
Ding!
伤心。
叮！
Plankton, I think I know
浮游生物，我想我知道
how we can push Krabs
out of business.
我们如何推动蟹蟹
破产了。
We'll lure the customers
underground
我们会吸引顾客
地下
with this gorgeous scenery.
伴随着这绚丽的风景。
Karen, please.
凯伦，请。
I'm trying to process
my emotions.
我正在尝试处理
我的情绪。
Karen, I think I know
凯伦，我想我知道
how we can push Krabs
out of business.
我们如何推动蟹蟹
破产了。
We'll lure the customers
underground
我们会吸引顾客
地下
with this gorgeous scenery!
有了这美丽的风景！
Man, I'm good!
伙计，我很好！
Cave dwellers!
穴居人！
Whoa!
哇！
Get back!
回来吧！
That's better.
这样更好。
From now on,
you shall be my minions,
从现在开始，
你将成为我的奴才，
servants to follow
my every order.
仆人跟随
我的每一个订单。
I decree this kingdom
to be called the Chum Caverns,
我下令这个王国
被称为楚姆洞穴，
and may the people
of Bikini Bottom
愿人民
比基尼下装
shudder in awe of its majesty.
对其威严感到敬畏。
Hurry up, mom.
快点，妈妈。
I want to see the Chum Caverns
before the line gets too long.
我想去看看密姆洞穴
在队伍变得太长之前。
Never you mind, Suzy.
没关系，苏西。
It's already too late for that.
已经太晚了。
Quick,
get in front of that kid.
快点，
走到那个孩子面前。
This is my spot.
这是我的地盘。
Splat!
啪！
You know, this stuff
is hideously inedible,
你知道，这个东西
是极其不可食用的，
but your decor is so amazing,
但你的装饰太棒了
I can't resist
spending my money here.
我无法抗拒
把我的钱花在这里。
Two orders of Chum Nuggets,
please.
两份 Chum Nuggets 订单，
请。
That certainly is chum,
那当然是密友，
and such steamy chumminess
deserves recompense.
和如此热气腾腾的亲密关系
值得报应。
Oh, I'll take that.
哦，我会接受的。
Eat your twisted, blackened,
moneygrubbing heart out, Krabs.
吃掉你扭曲的、变黑的，
蟹蟹们，贪图金钱的心。
I'm even profiting
off your most loyal ally.
我还盈利了
离开你最忠实的盟友。
I'm running out of space
for this stuff.
我的空间不足了
对于这个东西。
Got an empty safe
I can borrow, Krabs?
有一个空的保险箱
我可以借用吗，蟹蟹？
But seriously,
this is getting really heavy.
但说真的，
这真的变得很沉重。
Patrick,
isn't this place amazing?
帕特里克，
这个地方不是很棒吗？
Here's your Chum Nuggets,
buddy.
这是你的密友金块，
伙计。
Your Chum Kabob.
你的密友烤肉。
Uh, I guess you don't come
down here for the food, anyway.
呃，我猜你不会来
无论如何，来这里是为了食物。
You come down here to admire
the subterranean splendor
你来这里欣赏
地下的辉煌
of the Chum Caverns.
楚姆洞穴。
That and the gift shop.
那和礼品店。
Ooh, that's right, Patrick.
The gift shop!
哦，没错，帕特里克。
礼品店！
Yeah, baby.
I've got cavern fever!
是的，宝贝。
我得了洞穴热！
Where have you been?
你去哪儿了？
And what's that ridiculous thing
on your head?
那是什么可笑的事情
在你头上吗？
It's a Stalag-Miter.
这是一个石塔尖顶。
Available exclusively
at the Chum Caverns gift shop.
独家发售
在 Chum Caverns 礼品店。
How dare you spend
all the money I don't pay you
你怎么敢花钱
所有的钱我都不付给你
at me archrival's business?
关我宿敌的事？
Boy, Plankton's really
cleaning up down there,
男孩，浮游生物真的
清理那里，
which means the only way
to pick this business up
这意味着唯一的方法
接手这项业务
is to run it into the ground.
就是把它埋到地下。
Another order of Chum Balls.
又一份密友球。
Huh?
啊？
Krabs?
螃蟹？
What are you doing here?
你在这里做什么？
I'm here to steal back
me customers
我是来偷回来的
我的顾客
with the savory flavor
of a Krabby Patty.
带着咸味
蟹肉饼。
Now, go get it.
现在，去拿吧。
Krabs!
螃蟹们！
You can't just slither down here
你不能就这么滑下去
and steal all my customers.
并抢走我所有的顾客。
It's unethical.
这是不道德的。
Unethical?
不道德？
This is all perfectly legit.
这都是完全合法的。
I call full drilling rights
under me restaurant.
我称之为完全钻探权
我下面的餐厅。
Sea turtles!
He called it.
海龟！
他这样称呼它。
He always was good
with legal jargon.
他一直都很好
用法律术语。
All right, Krabs,
好吧，蟹蟹们，
if you think it's fair
to undercut my business,
如果你认为这是公平的
削弱我的生意，
then I'm gonna undercut you.
那我就削弱你了
How does it feel, Krabs,
蟹蟹感觉怎么样
being in the hole,
so to speak?
处于洞中时，
可以这么说吗？
Not well, I'd imagine.
不太好，我想。
Now, hold still
so I can bury you.
现在，保持不动
这样我就可以埋葬你。
Not if I bury you first.
如果我先埋葬你就不会。
Eh?
呃？
Fine, Krabs,
have it your way.
好吧，蟹蟹们，
随心所欲。
Oh!
哦！
Ah.
啊。
We're trapped, trapped,
trapped, I tell you!
我们被困住了，被困住了，
被困了，我告诉你！
This is all your fault.
这都是你的错。
I ought to boil and butter you
for this.
我应该把你煮沸并涂上黄油
为此。
Plankton, I don't think
浮游生物，我不认为
of our sitiation.
我们的情况。
We're trapped down here,
我们被困在这里了
as in, there is no way out!
就像，没有出路！
Ha!
哈!
There may be
no way out for you, Krabs,
可能有
蟹蟹，你没有出路，
but you needn't worry
about me.
但你不用担心
关于我。
My diminutive stature
allows me
我的身材娇小
允许我
to slip through rubble
with ease.
穿过瓦砾
轻松地。
I can't make it.
我做不到。
We're doomed!
我们注定了！
Uh-huh.
嗯嗯。
That's what I've been trying
to tell you.
这就是我一直在尝试的
告诉你。
Comfort me.
安慰我。
15 minutes later...
15分钟后...
Ah, look at us.
Old, gray.
啊，看看我们。
旧的，灰色的。
Nearing the end.
接近尾声了。
Say, Plankton,
说，浮游生物，
if we ever make it out of here
with our lives,
如果我们能离开这里
和我们的生活，
let's agree to work together.
让我们同意一起工作。
You're right, Krabs.
你说得对，蟹蟹。
Let's bury the hatchet
now and forever.
让我们冰释前嫌吧
现在和永远。
We have a deal.
我们达成协议。
No more bickering.
不再争吵。
No more skullduggery
of any kind.
不再有诈骗行为
任何类型的。
Yeah.
是的。
Hang on a minute.
等一下。
Don't you hear that?
你没听到吗？
Surprise!
惊喜！
You found us, boy!
你找到了我们，孩子！
Oh-ho!
I should pay you for this.
噢嗬！
我应该为此付钱给你。
Or just pay me for the job
I already do.
或者只是付钱给我这份工作
我已经这样做了。
Hey, Plankton,
we're free!
嘿，浮游生物，
我们自由了！
Where'd he go?
他去哪儿了？
I'm way ahead of you, Krabs.
我比你领先很多，蟹蟹。
You better not be trying
to steal me formula.
你最好不要尝试
偷我的配方。
I am, and I will.
我是，而且我会的。
But what about our deal?
但我们的交易呢？
What?
We're still working together.
什么？
我们仍然一起工作。
Come on, you're helping me
steal your formula.
来吧，你在帮助我
窃取你的公式。
That's it.
就是这样。
Just wait till I get me claws
on you.
等我抓到我的爪子
在你身上。
Ah!
啊!
Now to get that formula.
现在得到这个公式。
Satisfied with yourself,
Plankton?
对自己很满意，
浮游生物？
Now you trapped us all
underground.
现在你困住了我们所有人
地下。
But at least we're trapped
in a good restaurant.
但至少我们被困住了
在一家好餐馆里。
Captive customers?
俘虏客户？
I should have thought of this
sooner.
我应该想到这一点
早点。
Hmm, but without Squidward,
嗯，但是没有章鱼哥，
I need someone
to work the register.
我需要有人
操作寄存器。
♪ ♪